You, like I mentioned, with SpaceX, you give a lot
of people hope, and a lot of people look up
to you. Millions of people look up to you. If
we think about young people
in high school, maybe in college,
what advice would you give to them about
if they wanna try to do something big in this
world, they wanna really have a big positive impact, what
advice would you give them about their career, maybe about
life in general?
Try to be useful.
You do things that are useful to your fellow human
beings, to the world. It's very hard to be useful.
Very hard.
You know, are you contributing more than you consume?
You know, like,
like, can you
try to have a positive net contribution?
to society.
I think that's the thing to aim for.
Not to try to be sort of a leader for
just for the sake of being a leader or whatever.
A lot of the time, people who— a lot of
the time, the people you want as leaders are the
people who don't want to be leaders.
So,
if you can live a useful life,
that is a good life,
a life worth
having lived.
Um,
you know, and I, like I said,
I would, I would encourage people to
use the mental tools of physics and apply them broadly
in life.
They are the best tools.
When you think about education and self-education, what do you
recommend? So there's the university, there is
self-study. There is hands-on sort of finding a company or
a place or a set of people that do the
thing you're passionate about and joining them as early as
possible.
There's taking a road trip across Europe for a few
years and writing some poetry. Which trajectory do you suggest?
In terms of learning about how you can become useful?
as you mentioned, how you can have the most positive
impact?
I'd encourage people to read a lot of books.
Just read, like, I mean, basically try to ingest as
much information as you can
and try to also just develop a good general knowledge.
so you at least have like
a rough lay of the land of the knowledge landscape.
Like try to learn a little bit about a lot
of things, 'cause you might not know what you're really
interested— how would you know what you're really interested in
if you at least aren't like doing a
peripheral exploration broadly
of
the knowledge landscape?
And talk to people from different walks of life and
different
industries and professions and skills and occupations. Like, just try,
you know,
learn as much as possible.
Man's search for meaning.
Isn't the whole thing a search for meaning?
Yeah, what's the meaning of life and all, you know.
But just generally, like I said, I would encourage people
to read broadly
in many different subject areas.
And then try to find something where there's an overlap
of your talents and what you're interested in. So people
may be good at something, or they may have skill
at a particular thing, but they don't like doing it.
Mm-hmm.
So you wanna try to find a thing where you're—
that's a good combination of the things that you're inherently
good at, but you also like doing.
And reading is a super fast shortcut to figure out
which, where are you. You're both good at it, you
like doing it, and it will actually have positive impact.
Well, you gotta learn about things somehow. So, reading
a broad range, just really
read it, you know. One point when I was a
kid, I read through the encyclopedia.
So, that was pretty helpful.
And also things I didn't even know existed, law, law,
lots, obviously. It's like as broad as it gets. Encyclopedias
were digestible, I think, whatever, 40 years ago.
So, maybe read through the condensed version of the Encyclopedia
Britannica. I'd recommend that.
You can always skip subjects where you read a few
paragraphs and you know you're not interested, just jump to
the next one.
So, read the encyclopedia or skim through it.
But I put a lot of stock in, certainly have
a lot of respect for someone who puts in an
honest day's work
to do useful things.
And just generally to have
not a zero-sum mindset
or
have more of a
grow-the-pie mindset. If you sort of say,
when we see people, perhaps including some very smart people,
kind of taking an attitude of
doing things that seem morally questionable,
it's often because they have at a base axiomatic level
a zero-sum mindset.
Right.
without realizing it. They don't realize they have a zero-sum
mindset, or at least they don't realize it consciously.
And so if you have a zero-sum mindset, then the
only way to get ahead is by taking things from
others.
If the pie is fixed, then the only way to
have more pie is to take someone else's pie.
But this is false. Obviously the pie has grown dramatically
over time, the economic pie.
So In reality, you can have—
I overuse this analogy— you can have a lot of—
there's a lot of pie. Yeah, absolutely. Pie is not
fixed.
So, you really want to make sure you're not operating
without realizing it from a zero-sum mindset where the only
way to get ahead is to take things from others.
Then that's going to result in you trying to take
things from others, which is not Not good. It's much
better to work on
adding to the economic pie.
So, creating,
like I said, creating more than you consume,
doing more than you— yeah. So, that's a big deal.
I think there's a fair number of people in
finance that
do have a bit of a zero-sum mindset. I mean,
it's all walks of life. I've seen that. One of
the reasons
Rogan inspires me is he celebrates others a lot. There's
not creating a constant competition. Like, there's a scarcity of
resources. What happens when you celebrate others and you promote
others,
the ideas of others,
it actually grows that pie. I mean, it every— like,
the
resources become less scarce. And that applies in a lot
of kinds of domains. It applies in academia where a
lot of people are very,
see some funding for academic research as zero-sum, and it
is not. If you celebrate each other, if you make,
if you get everybody to be excited about AI, about
physics, about mathematics, I think there'd be more and more
funding, and I think everybody wins. Yeah, that applies I
think broadly.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.